<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20160922</CreaDate><CreaTime>14272200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20160922</ModDate><ModTime>14283000</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile><MapLyrSync>TRUE</MapLyrSync><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">AverageAbundanceSeaScallops.lyr</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">005</imsContentType></itemProps></DataProperties><SyncDate>20160922</SyncDate><SyncTime>14282300</SyncTime></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Average Abundance of Sea Scallops (SMAST)</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"/></presForm></idCitation><idAbs>This layer shows the average abundance (2003 - 2012) of Sea scallops, colored by percentile. Abundance of 1 or more represents an area with commercially viable scallop densities. This data product was created using the University of Massachusetts Dartmouth School of Marine Science and Technology (SMAST) video survey from 2003 through 2012 joined to the New England Fishery Management Council Swept Area Seabed Impact (SASI) model grid. The SMAST video survey covered the Continental Shelf from the southern Mid-Atlantic to the USA-Canadian border on eastern Georges Bank.</idAbs><idPurp>The main goal of this project was to provide a better picture of the marine environment on the highly productive U.S. Northeast Shelf, from the Hague Line to the Chesapeake. This project, which was managed by The Nature Conservancy (TNC) and funded by the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation, introduced spatial data products that will significantly advance the understanding of marine habitats and ecological function in the Northwest Atlantic. This study provided new information about several species groups observed in a video survey. Additionally, the project has provided a comprehensive baseline of information on the benthic habitat and associated oceanographic conditions on the U.S. Northeast Shelf at a scale that is useful to fisheries managers, spatial planners, and the wider community of stakeholders. </idPurp><idCredit>University of Massachusetts Dartmouth School of Marine Science and Technology (SMAST), The Nature Conservancy (TNC).</idCredit><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.3.0.4322</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></dataLang><searchKeys><keyword>Northwest Atlantic</keyword><keyword>Abundance</keyword><keyword>Scallop</keyword><keyword>SASI</keyword><keyword>SMAST</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This data set must be cited on all electronic and hard copy products using the language of the Data Set Credit. Neither SMAST nor The Nature Conservancy shall be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. Any sale, distribution, loan, or offering for use of these digital data, in whole or in part, is prohibited without the approval of SMAST and The Nature Conservancy. The use of these data to produce other GIS products and services with the intent to sell for a profit is prohibited without the written consent of SMAST and The Nature Conservancy. All parties receiving these data must be informed of these restrictions. SMAST and The Nature Conservancy shall be acknowledged as data contributors to any reports or other products derived from these data.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"/><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"/></mdLang><distInfo><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Layer</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20160922</mdDateSt></metadata>
